<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-14T20:35:27-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Victor Perez</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Just Walk Out</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/just-walk-out.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Just Walk Out" /><published>2018-04-04T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-04T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/just-walk-out</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/just-walk-out.html">&lt;p&gt;The better the medicine, the more frequent the usage. As usage increases, the urge to increase dosage arises, and addiction settles. This is how addiction works in my mind, though I’m sure the reality doesn’t match up to my own perception. When I think of apathy, I consider it in the same way that I consider my bullshit theory for addiction. Apathy is needed in small doses; you can’t care about everything, to try is a fruitless and maddening task. In the same vein, caring about nothing is as equally as terrible. Apathy breeds sloth and sloth breeds the other ‘a’: atrophy. I of course, say these things with the same ignorant confidence that I present my “addiction theory,” however in my own experiences this is what I’ve found to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a curious image I’ve found that relates to my experiences with Apathy. It features a skeleton in a running position, with a light blue gradient in the background. At the top, it’s titled with “JUST WALK OUT” with the subtext: “You can leave!!!” To the left of the skeleton, various situations are listed out: “Work, social thing, movies, home, class, dentist, clothes shoppi, too fancy weed store, cops if your quick, friend ships.” Finally at the bottom lies the call phrase: “If it sucks…. Hit da bricks!! - Real winners quit!” My friend Brenn and I have discussed the meaning behind this humorous image at length. Brenn focuses on the ending line, “real winners quit.” His interpretation of the joke is that in western society, there is an expectation that you never give up on anything. For example, dropping out of college is seen as one of the ultimate failures in America, even if it’s the necessary or best course of action. As for myself, I take it in the more literal sense. Fear of missing out is a very real thing, and often times you can find yourself in situations where you aren’t enjoying yourself, but are staying because you feel a sense of obligation. This is especially prominent in some of the friendships I’ve been in where I stay connectected to people because it was simply the easiest course of action, even when those friendships weren’t good for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both of these cases, the decisions are affected by the ultimately meaningless perception that other people will have of us. In order to avoid these sorts of situations, there needs to be a nugget of apathy available to lean on. If people think less of you for doing something that you truly believe needs to be done, that’s their problem. At least, that’s the way I choose to live my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorjperez.github.io/assets/img/justwalkout.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;Picture in question&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">The better the medicine, the more frequent the usage. As usage increases, the urge to increase dosage arises, and addiction settles. This is how addiction works in my mind, though I’m sure the reality doesn’t match up to my own perception. When I think of apathy, I consider it in the same way that I consider my bullshit theory for addiction. Apathy is needed in small doses; you can’t care about everything, to try is a fruitless and maddening task. In the same vein, caring about nothing is as equally as terrible. Apathy breeds sloth and sloth breeds the other ‘a’: atrophy. I of course, say these things with the same ignorant confidence that I present my “addiction theory,” however in my own experiences this is what I’ve found to be true.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/justwalkout.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Poster Density</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/music/poster-density.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poster Density" /><published>2018-03-30T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/music/poster-density</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/music/poster-density.html">&lt;p&gt;There is a place, hidden in plain sight. Chances are, if you attend or have attended West Virginia University, you have walked by it. Nestled deep inside the student union, there lies a wall of glass, and on the glass the U92 logo proudly rests. This is the college radio station; the source of Morgantown’s only alternative programming, and more importantly: one of my many homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open the glass door, and you’ll find yourself in a room surrounded by three walls of rusted red brick. Music posters are lined up neatly on the walls, and at the right lies another glass door to a small recording studio, which usually lies empty. If you’re not a staff member, the lady at the desk, Darlene, will probably ask what you need. If you are a staff member however, you’ll probably just walk by her, choosing to saying hello or not depending on how you feel about her presence. Once you get past Darlene, there is an intermediary room that connects to another recording studio. More posters outfit the walls, this time a little less evenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving onto the next room, you’ll find yourself in the main area of the station. Depending on the time your enter, you’ll find a few people hanging around (usually sports staff). There was a time when DJs took up every available seat, but after the strike, the station lies colder and emptier than usual. The music posters are outta control by this point, and in most spots you can hardly see the wall. Sections of the wall are dedicated to the news staff and sports staff, but the biggest pinboard belongs to the DJ staff. Sign-up sheets for dozens of specialty shows are tacked on. Take a closer look and you’ll find many repeated names: Trevor, Ed, Victor, Kate, and so on. The station has a painfully low amount of DJs, and the ones that are there work tirelessly to keep the airwaves interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this room, you have three different doorways. The most important is completely covered in stickers from various artists and record labels. In the top right, the extremely missable “Studio A” label blends in with all of the visual noise. Enter the doorway and you’ll find yourself in the DJ booth, where the music and transmitters are controlled from. The lighting is dim and colorful, and on the back wall lies a vast shelf packed with CDs that were once in rotation. Across from the shelf, the controls for the station sit next to two seperate record players. Large speakers hang from the ceiling, and in between lies a window to “Studio B”, the place where sports and news staff do their segments. It’s a painfully sterile and boring room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to the main room, there lies one more doorway, to the deepest part of the station. The desks of the music, assistant music, and program directors lie there. Poster and sticker wise, it has the highest density of the station. going There is a door to a CD archive that contains pictures of some former and current staff, as well as various musicians titled “The Door of Babes”. Finally there is a hallway that leads to the back entrance, a bathroom, and another vinyl/CD archive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">There is a place, hidden in plain sight. Chances are, if you attend or have attended West Virginia University, you have walked by it. Nestled deep inside the student union, there lies a wall of glass, and on the glass the U92 logo proudly rests. This is the college radio station; the source of Morgantown’s only alternative programming, and more importantly: one of my many homes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/dark_station.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Paper Code</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/tech/paper-code.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paper Code" /><published>2018-03-30T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/tech/paper-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/tech/paper-code.html">&lt;p&gt;As I’ve become more and more experienced as a programmer, one thing has abundantly clear: the less time you spend writing code, the better. Much like writing a book, if you just hop on your computer and start typing, you’ll eventually find yourself tangled in your own work, making something that is more or less impossible to work with. If you chose to continue working on the same poor foundation, more and more time will be spent dedicated to solving problems that you caused, that could have easily been prevent. It is because of this that the majority of my time is spent carefully deciphering what the problem is and planning out how I will solve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, a factorial program is one of the earliest programming puzzles you may encounter as a rookie programmer. The first step is understanding what a factorial is and how it behaves. This is the point where I whip out the programmer’s primary tools: pen and paper. Looking at the behavior of a factorial, I would trace it by hand on paper. 3 factorial is 1 x 2 x 3, 5 factorial is 1 x 2 x 3 x 4 x 5, and so on. It’s important to recognize the pattern in this situation: every number is multiplied by every factor before it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I know what a factorial is and how it operates, it’s still not time to leave the paper. The next step is the programmers second best friend: charts! I love charts, can’t get enough of them. It’s easy to get lost when following how a program executes, and charts make things clear. First I label it with the function name factorial(&lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt;) (a function is basically a formula that you write yourself). The &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt; value can be any number, so the program I write must be able to work with anything. First I look at cases where the program must fail. You can’t take the factorial of a negative number, or a number that doesn’t exist, so I mark that in a box in the top right. After a quick study of my previous findings, I recognize that I should use a special technique that is common for repeatable processes called recursion. Since taking the factorial of any number requires taking the factorial of the previous number before it, I can chain factorial operations based on what number I take in. It’s a little difficult to comprehend at first, but as an example, take 3 factorial and 2 factorial. 3 factorial is 3 x 2 x 1 and 2 factorial is 2 x 1. Another way to calculate 3 factorial is to multiply 2 factorial by 3. Using this logical, every factorial is essential &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt; x factorial(&lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt;) until &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt; equals 1. If you can’t exactly follow that, don’t think too hard about it. It’s harder to parse that logic in your mind, which is why a chart is essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it’s time to hop on the computer. This should be the easy part. Using whatever language I choose, I take all my notes and write the program. If something goes wrong, I can draw out each step on paper to help understand where I’ve made a mistake. If the solution is completely wrong, I hop off the computer again, and go back to the drawing board. Staring at the screen trying to solve a problem is usually very tiring, and fairly ineffective when it comes to more conceptual problems. Finally, once it’s all said and done, I calculate the factorials of various numbers on paper using a calculator, and input those into the factorial function. If everything checks out, the program is finished.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">As I’ve become more and more experienced as a programmer, one thing has abundantly clear: the less time you spend writing code, the better. Much like writing a book, if you just hop on your computer and start typing, you’ll eventually find yourself tangled in your own work, making something that is more or less impossible to work with. If you chose to continue working on the same poor foundation, more and more time will be spent dedicated to solving problems that you caused, that could have easily been prevent. It is because of this that the majority of my time is spent carefully deciphering what the problem is and planning out how I will solve it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/computerscience.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Flint</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/flint.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flint" /><published>2018-03-30T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/flint</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/flint.html">&lt;p&gt;It was another classic day in Morgantown. Cold enough to require a jacket, and hot enough to sweat in one. As I awoke from my light nap, I felt the thick humidity of the air as my shirt stuck to parts of my chest. Groggily, I went over to the kitchen and started the tea kettle for my evening coffee. It was around six in the evening, and I was following the usual thursday routine: go to class, take a nap, and head over to my college’s radio station to prepare for the five hours of music. This time however, I was adding a step. Nick Flynn was doing a reading in the downtown library, and it just so happened that it fit perfectly into my schedule. The little exposure I had of Flynn’s work impressed me, and there was no real reason not to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking into the downtown library, I asked the girl at the counter for directions to the Milano Reading Room. It had been a long time since I had been in this library, and I could exactly recall where it was. Traversing up the stairs, I felt the memories of the reading room rush in. I had only been there twice before to study, but this time it felt completely different. As I walked up the steps, I could hear light chatter slightly echo the wide chamber. Despite being there before,  I couldn’t help but feel an oppressive sense of grandeur while scanning the reading room. I say “room,” but really that’s a bit of a misnomer. In the moment it felt more like a very wide and tall hall than anything else. Dusty old bookcases lined the walls, broken up by old-looking paintings and busts. Looking right, rows of stiff wooden chairs pointed to an empty podium. Decisively avoiding the sugary refreshments, I took a seat in the back row, quietly acknowledging the english professor that mentioned this event to the class. After a minute or two, Will from that same class sat down next to me, and we had a quick chat before the event started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the reading itself, it had all the key points that you can come to expect from a these sorts of events. The somewhat lengthy and numerous introductions. Light humor mixed in, accompanied by that one guy who loudly chuckles at even the smallest quip. That one dude you’re trying very hard not to look at who had started a bunch of “twitter beef” with your friends a few hours earlier. Flynn was by and large, exactly what I expected. The way he manages to write so many words beautifully while only occasionally making things explicitly clear is what drew me to the event in the first place, and his description of the fire he survived as a child did not disappoint. The poetic prose he writes is enthralling, and hearing him read it aloud put a voice to what I had read the day before. The reading itself was fairly short, clocking in at around thirty minutes long. Walking out with Will, I succumbed to my temptation and picked up a chocolate cookie. Finally, I walked out into the rain to head over to my five hour radio shift.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">It was another classic day in Morgantown. Cold enough to require a jacket, and hot enough to sweat in one. As I awoke from my light nap, I felt the thick humidity of the air as my shirt stuck to parts of my chest. Groggily, I went over to the kitchen and started the tea kettle for my evening coffee. It was around six in the evening, and I was following the usual thursday routine: go to class, take a nap, and head over to my college’s radio station to prepare for the five hours of music. This time however, I was adding a step. Nick Flynn was doing a reading in the downtown library, and it just so happened that it fit perfectly into my schedule. The little exposure I had of Flynn’s work impressed me, and there was no real reason not to go.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/water.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Engineering Station</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/engineering-station.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Engineering Station" /><published>2018-03-21T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-21T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/engineering-station</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/engineering-station.html">&lt;p&gt;It was early October in the very recent year 2017, and I was standing at the PRT station thinking. The thoughts consumed me, sharply dulling all of my senses. Though the thoughts were focusing on a very bad thing, I strangely felt a neutral feeling while I unpacked each and every one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, do you remember me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly I could see. Before me stood a vaguely recognizable figure. After a short moment putting away my thoughts, I pushed out the words: “Aubri, right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, aren’t you Victor? I remember you from Culturas.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culturas: the student organization for hispanics. It was a name that beckoned the thoughts back.  Again, I paused to put them away. I responded. “How have you been? Haven’t seen you around in a while.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve been doing good, haven’t been to the club in a while sadly.” She paused. “Hey, you’re Puerto Rican right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puerto Rico. The thoughts broke out of the cage again. “Of course, why do you ask?” I knew why she asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How have you been holding up after hurricane Maria? Is your family alright?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s only a few people in my family I haven’t heard from, but they live in the places that didn’t get hit too hard.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I heard the island isn’t getting power back for six months,” said Aubri. Or was it me? The thoughts were screaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, it’s been pretty terrible,” I said. “The island is ruined.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The station lights suddenly flashed the word “BEECHURST”, and it was time for Aubri to leave. “I’m glad you family is at least safe, hope everything ends up okay,” she said before walking away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t recall responding, but I remember thinking about my family. I’ve never had a strong connection to my family, especially the ones that spoke spanish. The language barrier was too strong for me. Yet still, I was worried. Without water, heat stroke was a very real concern. Without power, there was no way to refrigerate my grandmother’s insulin. I was so distant from everything, I heard nothing. The short conversation with my sister I had the day before only fueled my worries. But I couldn’t worry. I had to worry about my studies above all else, and I couldn’t afford to stress about something I could do nothing about. The station lights suddenly flashed the words “WALNUT”, and it was time for me to leave the thoughts behind. Though I haven’t seen Aubri since then, a pleasant thought of her surfaced as I enjoyed my grandmother’s cooking over thanksgiving break. I appreciated it more than I ever have before.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">It was early October in the very recent year 2017, and I was standing at the PRT station thinking. The thoughts consumed me, sharply dulling all of my senses. Though the thoughts were focusing on a very bad thing, I strangely felt a neutral feeling while I unpacked each and every one of them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/station.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Running For Buckthorn</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/Running-For-Buckthorn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running For Buckthorn" /><published>2018-02-18T23:50:34-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-18T23:50:34-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/Running-For-Buckthorn</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/Running-For-Buckthorn.html">&lt;p&gt;Running from friends. Running from life. Running from family. No matter where I go, I can’t escape. Running from anxiety. Running from reality. Running from my future career. I’ve never been much of an athlete. My legs and my lungs are always in competition of what will give first. Running from my desires, because I felt like I was never worth them. Running from my needs, because other peoples’ were more important. Running is pointless and exhausting. Trying to justify why you’re running is almost as bad as the act of running itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I’ve been running my whole life. I’ve run figuratively from many things. Trying to avoid my problems, hoping they would go away. I’ve also run from things literally. That’s how I ended up in Morgantown, after all. The first time I ran away from home was at the greatest place on earth; Disney World. I was never a very calm child. What I craved most was excitement and thrills. My parents just wanted to take a nice picture in front of the flowers. Pictures ran very antithetical to what I craved as a child. They made me mad, and I loudly rebelled whenever they were taken. “Where are the roller coasters? I wanna ride the roller coasters,” I can imagine myself demanding loudly. Finally, I snapped. We were at a photo studio for all the Disney characters waiting in line to take a picture with Goofy. Can you imagine waiting in line for something that wasn’t a roller coaster? I was having none of that nonsense. My mother said something very poorly thought out in the moment: “If you don’t like it, you can just leave.” So I did. Eight year old me left his family and started wandering around in Epcot, one of the few Disney World parks without roller coasters, to find a roller coaster. Yet, I was a determined little child, and relentless in my unknowingly pointless search. After around thirty minutes of limitless freedom, I saw a horrifying sight: my aunt in a full speed sprint, high heels in hand. I tried running, but it was too late. She tackled me with full force, and started hitting and yelling at me for leaving and worrying my family. I don’t know what felt worse: the fact that all that running had been for nothing, or the high heels.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">Running from friends. Running from life. Running from family. No matter where I go, I can’t escape. Running from anxiety. Running from reality. Running from my future career. I’ve never been much of an athlete. My legs and my lungs are always in competition of what will give first. Running from my desires, because I felt like I was never worth them. Running from my needs, because other peoples’ were more important. Running is pointless and exhausting. Trying to justify why you’re running is almost as bad as the act of running itself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/theland.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Flaming Arcade</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/Flaming-Arcade.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flaming Arcade" /><published>2018-02-01T23:50:34-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-01T23:50:34-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/Flaming-Arcade</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/Flaming-Arcade.html">&lt;p&gt;In modern American society, there’s always this notation of forward motion. As it stands, we as a country are always “pressing the gas” for better or for worse. If you aren’t moving forward, you are a waste of space. You are left behind. You are forgotten. My hometown is not exempt from these suffocating societal bindings. My hometown has never stopped growing and expanding. Every time I come back from a semester of college, another Starbucks has opened up. Commutes take an additional 5 minutes. Housing values rise by a huge factor. The closest grocery store has once again been bought out and remodeled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t like this when I was younger. Or at least I never noticed it. The suburbs are no place for a child, despite the fact that they were constructed for the sole purpose of housing growing families. I spent most of my time in the living room, on the computer. In my peripheral I was comforted by the soft “livings” of my family. My father reading on the couch, or my mother dusting the shelf above the fireplace. In the evening we would all watch the television “together”, as is American tradition. And by watch I mean, the television would be on and playing a show, and everyone would be in the general vicinity, aside from my sister. I would still be on the computer of course, and my father would still be reading, but we would all be passively paying attention to what was going on. Occasional soft chuckles would burst from any one of us, and the ambient noise of keyboard typing and page turning hummed in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That living room now lies cold, even in my presence. My computer was moved to my room. Whatever my father was reading back than was replaced by vapid facebook videos on his tablet. My mother sits on a separate couch. The television still hums in the background, but it’s larger and nicer than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are now 14 Starbucks coffee shops in a five mile radius. The suburbs are no place for a child.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">In modern American society, there’s always this notation of forward motion. As it stands, we as a country are always “pressing the gas” for better or for worse. If you aren’t moving forward, you are a waste of space. You are left behind. You are forgotten. My hometown is not exempt from these suffocating societal bindings. My hometown has never stopped growing and expanding. Every time I come back from a semester of college, another Starbucks has opened up. Commutes take an additional 5 minutes. Housing values rise by a huge factor. The closest grocery store has once again been bought out and remodeled.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/house.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pah-scotch-way</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/Pahscotchway.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pah-scotch-way" /><published>2018-01-23T23:50:34-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T23:50:34-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/Pahscotchway</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/Pahscotchway.html">&lt;p&gt;It was the late afternoon, a Tuesday if I recall. I was sitting down with a hot cup of coffee after a day of classes. I’ve done this routine many times before. Sit down, study a bit, maybe get a refill or two, leave. While working on whatever particularly needed to get done that day, a conversation or two might catch my attention. It is a coffee shop after all, and people either sit down to chat or to work. The conversation topics are mostly mundane, but two men caught my attention through the soft music and light mummering of conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh I certainly do have a good life,” said the older man. He was adorned in a tan peacoat and business professional dress, though something about him told me he hadn’t show up to work today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Me too, I’m glad I get to travel,” said the younger man. He seemed in his late thirties, and was very cleanly dressed and groomed. “I visited Piscataway, and I couldn’t even pronounce the name right!” he chuckled. “I was on the phone trying to tell someone where I was and kept saying “Pah-scotch-way”, and finally they figured it out- I was talking about Piscataway!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They both chuckled quietly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know I actually went to grad school around there”, said the older man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I know where you’re talking about, my cousin might have went there too. How was that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, I never talked to the undergrads there, but I tell you- I always used to hang around the davis library. All of the girls hung around there!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another quiet chuckle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“New Jersey is a weird place. I was at lowes once and the cashier was around 17 years old. He kept saying to me as he checked me out, he said to me “beg?””. The young man paused reflectively. “I was very confused, and he kept saying “beg” to me until he finally pointed to bags and I was like “Ohhhhh, bag!””&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chuckling was out of control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t really speak New Jersian.”, stated the young man rather obviously. It was clear the conversation had long since died before I started listening. “Well I’m gonna havta get going now, we should chat again sometime.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well I’m not going to be around here to long. I’m down here for the open mic night, but I dunno how long I’ll be around town”.The younger man seemed a little disappointed at this revelation. “I’m pretty easy to find though, if you want to chat while I’m around.” the old man was far too nice for his own good.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">It was the late afternoon, a Tuesday if I recall. I was sitting down with a hot cup of coffee after a day of classes. I’ve done this routine many times before. Sit down, study a bit, maybe get a refill or two, leave. While working on whatever particularly needed to get done that day, a conversation or two might catch my attention. It is a coffee shop after all, and people either sit down to chat or to work. The conversation topics are mostly mundane, but two men caught my attention through the soft music and light mummering of conversation.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/cnf.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Bedroom</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/the-bedroom.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Bedroom" /><published>2018-01-11T23:50:34-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-11T23:50:34-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/the-bedroom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/nonfiction/the-bedroom.html">&lt;p&gt;The memory is faint, and very old. What it lacks in substance it makes up for with the very visceral senses and feelings. It’s an insignificant memory, mundane even. I am very young, living in the countryside of northern New York. The aroma of sawdust filled the room prominently, for reasons that are unknown and quite frankly not relevant. Lying down on my bed next to the sunny window, I have a book in hand. With the only source of light in the room being the window, I lean in, lazily reading a novel while a subtle, but relentless pounding fills my head. The pounding is restrictive, and only highlights my unfortunate situation: I am trapped in this room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feeling of being trapped is not a unique one. Whether it be literal or metaphorical, being trapped has constantly crept up again and again in my life. It brings out a very primal sort of panic in me, akin to drowning. As much as I fight, the fact that there is no escape doesn’t change. The only escape comes from what I choose to distract myself with. Rolling around in my bed, the book was my ward of choice for this occasion. Suddenly, the slow creaking of a door resonates throughout the room. Almost instinctively, I ensure the book is hidden from sight and freeze. Despite being so young, I am not naive enough to think my mother is fooled by this move. After all, my earlier protest was very vocal and passionate. I always hated napping.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">The memory is faint, and very old. What it lacks in substance it makes up for with the very visceral senses and feelings. It’s an insignificant memory, mundane even. I am very young, living in the countryside of northern New York. The aroma of sawdust filled the room prominently, for reasons that are unknown and quite frankly not relevant. Lying down on my bed next to the sunny window, I have a book in hand. With the only source of light in the room being the window, I lean in, lazily reading a novel while a subtle, but relentless pounding fills my head. The pounding is restrictive, and only highlights my unfortunate situation: I am trapped in this room.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/bedroom.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Technological Waves and the Music Industry</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/music/tech/Technological-Waves-and-the-Music-Industry.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Technological Waves and the Music Industry" /><published>2017-11-05T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2017-11-05T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/music/tech/Technological-Waves-and-the-Music-Industry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/music/tech/Technological-Waves-and-the-Music-Industry.html">&lt;p&gt;NO MATTER THE INDUSTRY, technology has brought large changes to how things in our society function. The lightning fast pace of technology has hit the music industry in full force, and brought huge change with it. One of the biggest changes has been the introduction of web-based music streaming, where fans can access a huge and growing library of music for a small monthly fee, or even for free with advertisements. This is hugely different from how things worked in the past, where you would need to pay $10 per album in order to listen on demand. Now for around $10 a month, you can access a huge and ever-growing library of music. This is a huge boon for music enthusiasts and general consumers, but what about the artists? How do they make up for the lost revenue? Who eats the loss when it comes to the greatest deal in music? The answer is; eventually everyone. Music streaming services such as Spotify and Apple Music are a net negative on the music industry as a whole, and are not sustainable in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to understand what exactly the problem is with the music streaming service model, you have to understand how record labels and musicians have reacted to them. First, there has been a noticeable increase of live performances since music streaming has been brought to the mainstream (Naveed). Not only are artists touring more, their audiences have also been increasing due to the discovery aspects of music streaming. Merchandising is also something that has become a lot more prominent. Hip-hop artists in particular often tie in their own merchandise and branding. Vinyl, while still a pretty niche market, has also been on the rise the last few years. Lastly, branding deals have become huge in the hip hop subculture, and consumer fashion brands such as Adidas and even Nautica pay rappers large amounts of money to wear their clothing in the public eye. Streaming revue makes up a very small portion of the money artists earn for their work. But there is a caveat here; certain genres and artists cannot make use of some of these revenue streams. For genres of music that aren’t suitable for live performance, or artists that physically cannot perform due to medical or financial reasons, that revenue stream is completely unavailable. These factors have also contributed to hip hop being the dominant genre, since more revenue contributes to more competition and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some may argue that there isn’t much wrong with this picture. After all, at any every point in popular music culture at least one genre has dominated and created disproportionate amounts of revenue compared to others. The difference between now and the past has been caused in the shift in how the importance of certain revenue streams has changed. With recorded music earning less and less revenue, more pressure has been put on the other (potentially inaccessible) sources. So how does the music industry make streaming a more viable revenue source for recorded artists? The obvious solution is to increase the per-play rate from $0.004611 to something more generous, but most music streaming sites like Spotify don’t even make money to begin with, and increasing the per-play rate could be catastrophic (Wlömert). The real solution lies in the strength of music streaming; discovery. As stated before, music streaming services such as Spotify have a little problem when it comes to revenue. Spotify only exists because investors still believe it has the potential for much greater things due to how widely used and recognized. If music streaming as a culture fails, the current industry will destabilize. In order to provide artists with more revenue, the issue needs to be tackled at two ends: the record label’s end and the music streaming side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first point to address is that money doesn’t come from nowhere. A customer listening to a song does not generate a significant amount of money. The real money comes from the customers and their listening habits. Spotify in particular has a big enough market share to make the data analytics they gain from customers valuable. Big and small record labels could both benefit greatly from this data. For larger labels, seeing what generates the most streaming revenue or what the habits of consumers who listen to bigger hits are can be used to create more revenue for the label in the long term. For smaller labels, being able to see the listening habits of niche audiences they are trying to target can make it easier for smaller artists to gain more fans and thus, generate more income for the labels from other revenue sources. How does this solve the issue for smaller recorded artists? First, music streaming sites such as Spotify are able to finally make a profit by selling the data to record labels. Record labels are able to use this data to gain more money from other potential revenue sources such as live touring and merchandising. This lets the more performance orientated artists subsidize smaller recording-orientated artists, and thus create a more healthy ecosystem that unfortunately depends more on labels and big corporations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn’t an easy way to solve the current problem that the music industry has. There are way too many factors and moving parts, and not enough long term data on the actual impact streaming has had. For some artists and consumers, the current landscape of the music industry isn’t even a problem. The fact of the matter is that it only takes one major technological breakthrough to cause a giant storm in the music industry. What may be a solution one day could turn into a threat. After all, music streaming was created to solve online piracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;Works Cited&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Krukowski, Damon. “Making Cents.” Pitchfork, 14 Nov. 2012, pitchfork.com/features/article/8993-the-cloud/. Accessed 15 Sept. 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naveed, Kashif, et al. “Co-Evolution between streaming and live music leads a way to the sustainable growth of music industry – Lessons from the US experiences.” Technology in Society, vol. 50, 2017, pp. 1–19., doi:10.1016/j.techsoc.2017.03.005.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wlömert, Nils, and Dominik Papies. “On-Demand streaming services and music industry revenues — Insights from Spotify’s market entry.” International Journal of Research in Marketing, vol. 33, no. 2, 2016, pp. 314–327., doi:10.1016/j.ijresmar.2015.11.002.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">NO MATTER THE INDUSTRY, technology has brought large changes to how things in our society function. The lightning fast pace of technology has hit the music industry in full force, and brought huge change with it. One of the biggest changes has been the introduction of web-based music streaming, where fans can access a huge and growing library of music for a small monthly fee, or even for free with advertisements. This is hugely different from how things worked in the past, where you would need to pay $10 per album in order to listen on demand. Now for around $10 a month, you can access a huge and ever-growing library of music. This is a huge boon for music enthusiasts and general consumers, but what about the artists? How do they make up for the lost revenue? Who eats the loss when it comes to the greatest deal in music? The answer is; eventually everyone. Music streaming services such as Spotify and Apple Music are a net negative on the music industry as a whole, and are not sustainable in the long term.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/computerscience.jpg" /></entry></feed>