<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/personal-blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/personal-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-21T22:35:55-04:00</updated><id>/personal-blog/</id><title type="html">Victor Perez</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Vomit</title><link href="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/Vomit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vomit" /><published>2019-08-21T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-21T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/Vomit</id><content type="html" xml:base="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/Vomit.html">&lt;p&gt;In a moment I was awake, stomach churning and head tilting. Knowing what was coming, I frantically felt around for the remote in the half-lit intensive care unit. Then it came: blood. So much blood. Leaking through the gaps in my bound together teeth. I could do nothing but lurch and heave as I vomited blood onto my hospital blanket. There was no chance to reach for the suction tube on my left; I gripped tightly on the rails of the hospital bed every time I passed blood. Finally, two nurses rushed in to assist me, sucking up the blood and vomit into the half-filled jar behind me. My eyes were moist as I laid back waiting for the morphine and anti-nausea medication to hit the bloodstream. The nurses changed my sheets, my mother came back from the bathroom, and I fell asleep out of exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I woke up, I was finally faced with good news: the tube running from my nose to my stomach would finally be removed. Despite the incredible amount of discomfort from it being taken, I was filled with relief. I could breath, and the horrible feeling in my throat was gone. More importantly, I could move. While thankful I didn’t require a catheter after surgery, going to the bathroom in my bed was less than ideal. After two days, I could stand up and use the bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I looked at my face in the mirror after my double jaw surgery, I could only think of how big a mistake I made. My face blew up like a balloon, and underneath my jaw was a sack of skin the size of an orange. Was this the new face I was promised after all these years? Of course not. But I was hopped up on too many drugs and barely enough sleep to make that mental connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually a wheelchair came to pick me up and locate me to a normal recovery room. After another day of taking pain and nausea meds and drinking soup stock to keep me alive, I was wheeled out of the hospital. I would go on to vomit again a week later, though this time I was left on my own to clear out everything from my mouth. The things I do for my jaw.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">In a moment I was awake, stomach churning and head tilting. Knowing what was coming, I frantically felt around for the remote in the half-lit intensive care unit. Then it came: blood. So much blood. Leaking through the gaps in my bound together teeth. I could do nothing but lurch and heave as I vomited blood onto my hospital blanket. There was no chance to reach for the suction tube on my left; I gripped tightly on the rails of the hospital bed every time I passed blood. Finally, two nurses rushed in to assist me, sucking up the blood and vomit into the half-filled jar behind me. My eyes were moist as I laid back waiting for the morphine and anti-nausea medication to hit the bloodstream. The nurses changed my sheets, my mother came back from the bathroom, and I fell asleep out of exhaustion.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/personal-blog/juxt.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">On Vestoj</title><link href="/personal-blog/blog/fashion/On-Vestoj.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Vestoj" /><published>2019-07-27T00:22:34-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-27T00:22:34-04:00</updated><id>/personal-blog/blog/fashion/On-Vestoj</id><content type="html" xml:base="/personal-blog/blog/fashion/On-Vestoj.html">&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I’ve grown tired of internet communities. Once a primary focus of my spare time, the internet allowed me to connect to people in previously unreachable places, with knowledge of things I wasn’t even aware existed. Unfortunately, I found that some people should remain unreachable, and was driven away by the vile words and remarks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the very end, I managed to take a few things with me. In particular, a fashion related community was discussing other, more academic resources. It drew my attention, and eventually after souring the provided resources I landed myself on the home page of vestoj.com. The design stood out to me from traditional fashion related websites; it had a simple, ad-free layout. There was a large focus on the text and the text alone, and every article had a diverse set of sources. After reading the article &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vestoj.com/beggars-and-choosers/&quot;&gt;Beggars And Choosers&lt;/a&gt; by Johannes Lenhard&lt;/em&gt;, I was hooked. Lenhard wasn’t just talking about clothes, or runway shows. He wrote about poverty, and psychology, and how they could be viewed under the lens of fashion. It’s a rare thing to have a conversation about, and Vestoj housed a goldmine of articles just like it. I wasn’t seeing random people talk about dressing for dates, or the new streetwear lookbook they were designing. I was seeing the connection between fashion and life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I’m explaining it in the most dramatic way possible, if only to mirror the feeling I was overcome with upon my discovery. As soon as the eighth issue, On &lt;em&gt;Authenticity&lt;/em&gt;, was released, I paid $30 for a copy and read it cover to cover. Authenticity! What an incredible subject to cover in the age of easily accessible fashion replicas. Except it wasn’t just about it clothes. With Vestoj, it’s never that simple. The essay &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vestoj.com/acting-as-if/&quot;&gt;Acting As If&lt;/a&gt; by Michelle Millar Fisher&lt;/em&gt; was so close to my own life experiences that it remains something I re-read regularly. That same week, I hosted a “No Limits” show at my college’s radio station (A four hour segment of whatever audio content you could dream of), and read the article &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vestoj.com/the-making-of-a-star/&quot;&gt;The Making of a Star&lt;/a&gt; by Philippa Snow&lt;/em&gt; live on air while &lt;em&gt;Aphex Twin&lt;/em&gt; played in the background. I wanted everyone to hear what these people had to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vestoj remains an important part of my life. The website you’re reading this on is directly inspired by it. It’s fueled my interest in fashion and society, and even my own writing. I’m forever grateful for the London College of Fashion for funding it, and for Anja Aronowsky Cronberg for founding and editing it. If you still don’t quite understand what Vestoj is, here’s the words from “The Platform for Critical Thinking On Fashion” itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vestoj is a forum where academia, the museum world and the fashion industry can work together and with active communication. We write about the cultural phenomenon that is fashion in a manner that opens up for dialogue between theory and practice in order to raise awareness for fashion as a cultural phenomena and field of research and cultivate an even greater understanding for the discipline. Vestoj will exist outside of seasonally-based trends and news-focused articles. Instead we aim to encourage and champion the critical and independent voice within fashion as well as absolute creative freedom. In order to ensure that we remain free in thought and action Vestoj will have no advertising. Vestoj focuses solely on sartorial matters, bringing together academia and industry in a bid to combine academic theory, critical thinking and a bit of good old fashioned glamour.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">Over the years, I’ve grown tired of internet communities. Once a primary focus of my spare time, the internet allowed me to connect to people in previously unreachable places, with knowledge of things I wasn’t even aware existed. Unfortunately, I found that some people should remain unreachable, and was driven away by the vile words and remarks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/personal-blog/vestoj.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Keep Smoking, I Still Love You</title><link href="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/Keep-Smoking-I-Still-Love-You.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keep Smoking, I Still Love You" /><published>2019-04-22T06:42:34-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-22T06:42:34-04:00</updated><id>/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/Keep-Smoking-I-Still-Love-You</id><content type="html" xml:base="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/Keep-Smoking-I-Still-Love-You.html">&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember, I’ve found the smell of cigarettes comforting. In the far reaches of my memory are scenes of my grandfather’s kitchen, where I sat waiting for him while he was out on the porch. The door opens as someone enters the house, and I catch the ethereal scent of cigarette smoke as the door quickly closes behind them. I don’t have a particularly close connection to my grandfather, or even his house for that matter. Nonetheless, any time I notice the smell, it brings a wave of comfort and pleasant feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after four years, I remain surprised at the amount of people who smoke cigarettes in this town. Back at home, it was a rarity to see someone smoke unless you went into the city. I’ve lost count of the people I know in Morgantown who smoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of cigarettes I’ve smoked remains in the single digits, and will probably stay that way for the rest of my lifetime. Kate was the first person I smoked with. During parties we would occasionally both become overwhelmed, and relax on the porch together. For whatever reason, she only smokes when she drinks, and we were able to enjoy the quiet company of each other and the cool midnight air. I adore thinking of those moments, each tied together by the memory of her lit cigarette. Eventually one day the siren smell of her clove cigarette hit me, and I innocently requested a puff. The flavor of clove jumped out on me, and lingered on my lips as it passed it to hers. I can’t recall anything else about that day: just her and I, passing that single black cigarette back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve grown to find Morgantown comforting. Previously the aggressiveness of this town frightened me, but those around me have helped me enjoy my presence here. There are times I think about my fear of leaving and wonder if I’ve been conditioned to love this town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time I smoked was with Kate. We were passing each other a clove cigarette, from a pack I bought for her. There was a sense of guilt radiating from her about the passing on of her habit. After a short while of her mincing words, I decided to stop before it truly did become a habit. That day is burned into my memory: she was wearing a long dress with flowers, and we sat together on the steps behind the college radio station. I didn’t sleep well that night, the pain of hurting each other kept me awake. I still miss the intimacy of sharing cigarettes with her on porches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I left Morgantown, I would be leaving Kate behind. My head grows light and my eyes moisten when I think about this. She’s been very upfront about wanting me to leave for a better life, but I can feel the hesitation. Would it be that bad to stay?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">For as long as I can remember, I’ve found the smell of cigarettes comforting. In the far reaches of my memory are scenes of my grandfather’s kitchen, where I sat waiting for him while he was out on the porch. The door opens as someone enters the house, and I catch the ethereal scent of cigarette smoke as the door quickly closes behind them. I don’t have a particularly close connection to my grandfather, or even his house for that matter. Nonetheless, any time I notice the smell, it brings a wave of comfort and pleasant feelings.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/personal-blog/porch.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">This Town</title><link href="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/This-Town.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This Town" /><published>2018-04-27T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-27T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/This-Town</id><content type="html" xml:base="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/This-Town.html">&lt;p&gt;There isn’t enough room in this fucking town. Too many cars on the road, too many people in the streets. Too many bad landlords and musty clubs. Too many deadbeat townies and entitled students. Everyone has an opinion of Morgantown: it’s rusty, it’s dusty. It’s too boring, it’s too wild. It’s hard to pin down what exactly Morgantown is to the diverse set of people that inhabit it. That being said, this town is an intersection, a rest stop, for so many people. Morgantown is never really an intentional destination. You always just “end up” there for one reason or another. How did I end up here, in this small town packed to the brim?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t supposed to go West Virginia University. I feel like that’s a common feeling for people I’ve talked to, though admittedly it’s not a very large sample size. West Virginia isn’t exactly a sexy or well known state outside of sports, and the high acceptance rate and party reputation makes people doubt the quality of education (as if all public universities don’t meet some minimum standard of excellence). Yet here I am, enrolled in the university, for better or for worse. Despite being a pretty poor student in highschool, I aimed high college wise, applying to around eleven in total: six in United States and five in the United Kingdom. Since this was the first major decision I was making in my life, I had this idea that the more schools I applied to the more choices I would have. Little did I know at the time, there was more to choosing a college than simply getting in.
There’s too many people in this fucking town. I’m sure if you’ve ever driven here you’ve said that to yourself at one point or another. Being a town in West Virginia, my sister had this expectation that it was full of white racist southerners  and worried about me living there as a Hispanic man. Thanks to the university however, there is no visible pattern to the people that you might come across. One moment you might be talking to someone with a classic Texan accent; another you might be talking to someone who barely speaks English. I suppose if you’ve ever lived in a large city or even another college town you might have experienced this phenomenon; however, given that Morgantown is a small town in the middle of the Appalachia, it never ceases to surprise me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I visited Morgantown. And by Morgantown, I really mean the University. It was rainy and humid, much like right now, and nearly every other day in this town. After a long trip from my home in Richmond, Virginia, I was sitting on the tour bus with my parents, seeing the things that the university wanted me to see. Which for the most part meant that we saw very little of the town itself. Instead, as we traveled through the snaking roads and steep hills, we witnessed such riveting sights like Woodburn hall with its signature dusty red bricks and clock tower. Then came the especially modern recreation center that I would spend my future days walking through to get to class. The one destination that really stuck with me was the towers housing complex, where a student shouted loudly: “WVU sucks!” as we walked by. I hadn’t chosen where I was planning on going to school by that point, but I remember thinking to myself something along the lines of: “In some poetically messed up way, I’m gonna end up going to this place.”
There’s too many clubs in this fucking town. Yet somehow I am constantly told that there is nothing to do here. Those people aren’t wrong I guess. In the absence of more interesting things, alcoholism is a very attractive hobby. I’ve given up on counting the amount of active bars and clubs that pop up and close down around the downtown area. On weekend nights, the streets are packed with students and townies alike, looking for a good time in one form or another. For the sports minded, there are tailgates and sports bars to drink at. For the more hip students, frat houses are the main drinking hotspots. I personally choose to drink in the dusty old neighborhoods with the other “alternative” students. For the teetotalers out there, I’m not really sure what else you could do in this town. Or at least, I’ve never cared enough to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrestled a lot with deciding where I was going to go to school. Out of the five United Kingdom universities I applied to, I miraculously was accepted to four (most likely because they didn’t need to see my embarrassingly bad transcript). I had my heart set on Durham University, an ivy league university with an ivy league price tag. The grandiose Norman architecture was enthralling to me, and the strength of its Computer Science program made it a top pick for me. Going to school internationally however, wasn’t something economically feasible considering I was going to be picking up most of the bill myself. I remember acutely the feeling of opening a letter from West Virginia University, knowing in the back of my mind that the scholarship I was offered was too good to pass up. I had a choice to make, and in the end I made the economically responsible one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s too many hills in this fucking town. I’ve never felt the need to visit the gym while living in Morgantown. No matter my destination, there’s always a guarantee that there will be at least two uphill slogs. It’s especially bad if you ever have to get to the downtown center of campus: every incoming path has a hill. You can choose the shortest distance and face the steep set of stairs, or you can choose to approach from the downtown area and face a long, but more gradual slope. I end up walking a lot as a consequence of not owning a car, and I’m sure everyone here that does the same has amazing calves. Morgantown wouldn’t be the same without its characteristic hills. They are a constant reminder of the tiring nature of the this town.
I was exhausted after the six hour drive it took to when I finally moved to Morgantown. Not only because of the journey, but because of all the years I was boxed in those Virginia suburbs. I had always hated living there, and I had an intense desire to get as far away from my hometown as possible. Moving to another country would have accomplished this easily, but I guess settling with Morgantown wasn’t such a bad idea either in retrospect. Morgantown runs antithetical to the suburbs in about every way. For one thing, the suburbs are flat and spralling; so spralling that it’s impossible to get anywhere in a reasonable fashion without a car. In Morgantown, the public transportation situation is quite nice if you’re a student, and the horribly steep hills made everything be built compactly, and thus easy to traverse on foot. There’s also a sense of community missing from the suburbs; rarely do I ever come across a familiar face when going about my day. Morgantown is so central and focused that it’s impossible for me to go about my day without running into someone I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sports never seem to stop in this fucking town. It sometimes feels like I’m the only one that doesn’t seem to care about WVU football. During the spring semester, I only tend to keep track of when the football games start and end, lest I become trapped in the sea of blue and gold wearing the non-standard colors. It’s not like I don’t understand the obsession that people have with sports. It’s an easy thing to get hyped up about, and as I said before: it’s a convenient excuse to drink. Still, being woken up by someone blaring Country Roads at 7am on a Saturday makes me somewhat loathe the sports-fanatical culture. I’m sure if I was a sports fan Morgantown would be heaven for me, but there’s nothing I can really do about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if my first semester in Morgantown is considered abnormal or not. My assigned roommate at Arnold hall dropped out before the semester even started, so I had an entire room to my own self. Having that much space all to myself would have been amazing if Arnold hall was even a little decent, but there was no air conditioning in the entire building so I was mostly just hot for a while. Being away from the suburbs for the first time was a strange experience for me. Living downtown meant that I had access to anywhere I could walk, and I never really felt like I was trapped in my house like I was in the suburbs. This was all too much for young me to process however, and it took me a while to appreciate how lucky I was to be in the heart of Morgantown. I spent most of my time happily locked in my dorm room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s too many homeless people in this fucking town. If you look closely enough, you can see some of the metal anti-homeless spikes that line previously flat pieces of concrete on high street, or the benches with “convenient” arm rests placed in the middle. Every time I see those disgustingly cruel pieces of architecture I visualize a group of men in a room, deciding how much money they are willing to spend to deprive the homeless of a spot to lie down on. I’ve never volunteered at a homeless shelter or anything, much less even acknowledged the existence of a man who “just needed change for the meter,” so I guess I shouldn’t really be claiming moral high ground anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember the day I started to form an appreciation for Morgantown. A friend had recommended me a restaurant in the downtown area, which conveniently was only a short walk away. Slowly making my way down high street, I took note of the many interesting sights: homeless people sitting on the steps of a baptist church, a coca-cola branded mural, and a man blasting his music loud enough for everyone in the entire town to hear. After a short while, I arrived at my destination; a small hole in the wall restaurant on one of the side streets. As I walked in, I was greeted not only by the woman at the counter, but the chef in the back too. In the corner, daytime Japanese television played next a wall that proudly displayed pictures of the menu items. Two entire walls had shelves filled with Japanese books, and the tiny dining space was packed full of happy patrons. While I sat down and ate my meal, one thing stood out to me more than anything else: as customers would leave, the chef would be sure to thank each and every one of them. I wonder how many total times Yama has thanked me considering I manage to eat there almost every other week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s too many familiar faces in this fucking town. It seems like I can’t go anywhere without seeing someone whose existence I must awkwardly acknowledge: the man in a cowboy hat who picks up trash along high street. The baristas at the coffee shop I frequent on a daily basis. The guy I met at a party once who also frequents said coffee shop. You’d think it would be easy to avoid people in a place as big as Morgantown, but if you hang out at the same spots all the time I guess it’s kind of inevitable that you’ll see the same people. I should be more appreciative of those familiar faces, especially the man in the student union who gives me a joyous “have a wonderful day,” as I pass by his office. Due to the nature of Morgantown, there’s too many faces I’ve grown to like that have just disappeared, never to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have lived in Morgantown for three years now, and I still don’t know if I made the right choice in coming here. In the moment, you could say I made the right choice, but would I have done the same if I knew what I know now? Even with the benefit of retrospect, I’m not too certain. I’ve got nothing but good things to say about the quality of the education at WVU, and the town needs the university just as much as the university needs the town. One thing is certain in my mind: once I leave, I’ll never forget Morgantown and the people who have inhabited it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn’t enough room in this fucking town. Too many familiar faces. Too many good weekends. Too many nice people and their nice small business. Too many conversations struck up by strangers. Too many good places to eat. Too many comfy concert venues. Morgantown is as easy to love as it is to hate, but I didn’t know that going in. Maybe you have your own “Morgantown,” or maybe you’re still waiting for it to show up. Either way, it’s never too late to take some time to look around your own town.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">There isn’t enough room in this fucking town. Too many cars on the road, too many people in the streets. Too many bad landlords and musty clubs. Too many deadbeat townies and entitled students. Everyone has an opinion of Morgantown: it’s rusty, it’s dusty. It’s too boring, it’s too wild. It’s hard to pin down what exactly Morgantown is to the diverse set of people that inhabit it. That being said, this town is an intersection, a rest stop, for so many people. Morgantown is never really an intentional destination. You always just “end up” there for one reason or another. How did I end up here, in this small town packed to the brim?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/personal-blog/morgantown.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Just Walk Out</title><link href="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/just-walk-out.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Just Walk Out" /><published>2018-04-04T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-04T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/just-walk-out</id><content type="html" xml:base="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/just-walk-out.html">&lt;p&gt;The better the medicine, the more frequent the usage. As usage increases, the urge to increase dosage arises, and addiction settles. This is how addiction works in my mind, though I’m sure the reality doesn’t match up to my own perception. When I think of apathy, I consider it in the same way that I consider my bullshit theory for addiction. Apathy is needed in small doses; you can’t care about everything, to try is a fruitless and maddening task. In the same vein, caring about nothing is as equally as terrible. Apathy breeds sloth and sloth breeds the other ‘a’: atrophy. I of course, say these things with the same ignorant confidence that I present my “addiction theory,” however in my own experiences this is what I’ve found to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a curious image I’ve found that relates to my experiences with Apathy. It features a skeleton in a running position, with a light blue gradient in the background. At the top, it’s titled with “JUST WALK OUT” with the subtext: “You can leave!!!” To the left of the skeleton, various situations are listed out: “Work, social thing, movies, home, class, dentist, clothes shoppi, too fancy weed store, cops if your quick, friend ships.” Finally at the bottom lies the call phrase: “If it sucks…. Hit da bricks!! - Real winners quit!” My friend Brenn and I have discussed the meaning behind this humorous image at length. Brenn focuses on the ending line, “real winners quit.” His interpretation of the joke is that in western society, there is an expectation that you never give up on anything. For example, dropping out of college is seen as one of the ultimate failures in America, even if it’s the necessary or best course of action. As for myself, I take it in the more literal sense. Fear of missing out is a very real thing, and often times you can find yourself in situations where you aren’t enjoying yourself, but are staying because you feel a sense of obligation. This is especially prominent in some of the friendships I’ve been in where I stay connectected to people because it was simply the easiest course of action, even when those friendships weren’t good for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both of these cases, the decisions are affected by the ultimately meaningless perception that other people will have of us. In order to avoid these sorts of situations, there needs to be a nugget of apathy available to lean on. If people think less of you for doing something that you truly believe needs to be done, that’s their problem. At least, that’s the way I choose to live my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorjperez.github.io/Personal-Blog/assets/img/justwalkout.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;Picture in question&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">The better the medicine, the more frequent the usage. As usage increases, the urge to increase dosage arises, and addiction settles. This is how addiction works in my mind, though I’m sure the reality doesn’t match up to my own perception. When I think of apathy, I consider it in the same way that I consider my bullshit theory for addiction. Apathy is needed in small doses; you can’t care about everything, to try is a fruitless and maddening task. In the same vein, caring about nothing is as equally as terrible. Apathy breeds sloth and sloth breeds the other ‘a’: atrophy. I of course, say these things with the same ignorant confidence that I present my “addiction theory,” however in my own experiences this is what I’ve found to be true.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/personal-blog/justwalkout.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Poster Density</title><link href="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/music/poster-density.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poster Density" /><published>2018-03-30T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/music/poster-density</id><content type="html" xml:base="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/music/poster-density.html">&lt;p&gt;There is a place, hidden in plain sight. Chances are, if you attend or have attended West Virginia University, you have walked by it. Nestled deep inside the student union, there lies a wall of glass, and on the glass the U92 logo proudly rests. This is the college radio station; the source of Morgantown’s only alternative programming, and more importantly: one of my many homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open the glass door, and you’ll find yourself in a room surrounded by three walls of rusted red brick. Music posters are lined up neatly on the walls, and at the right lies another glass door to a small recording studio, which usually lies empty. If you’re not a staff member, the lady at the desk, Darlene, will probably ask what you need. If you are a staff member however, you’ll probably just walk by her, choosing to saying hello or not depending on how you feel about her presence. Once you get past Darlene, there is an intermediary room that connects to another recording studio. More posters outfit the walls, this time a little less evenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving onto the next room, you’ll find yourself in the main area of the station. Depending on the time your enter, you’ll find a few people hanging around (usually sports staff). There was a time when DJs took up every available seat, but after the strike, the station lies colder and emptier than usual. The music posters are outta control by this point, and in most spots you can hardly see the wall. Sections of the wall are dedicated to the news staff and sports staff, but the biggest pinboard belongs to the DJ staff. Sign-up sheets for dozens of specialty shows are tacked on. Take a closer look and you’ll find many repeated names: Trevor, Ed, Victor, Kate, and so on. The station has a painfully low amount of DJs, and the ones that are there work tirelessly to keep the airwaves interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this room, you have three different doorways. The most important is completely covered in stickers from various artists and record labels. In the top right, the extremely missable “Studio A” label blends in with all of the visual noise. Enter the doorway and you’ll find yourself in the DJ booth, where the music and transmitters are controlled from. The lighting is dim and colorful, and on the back wall lies a vast shelf packed with CDs that were once in rotation. Across from the shelf, the controls for the station sit next to two seperate record players. Large speakers hang from the ceiling, and in between lies a window to “Studio B”, the place where sports and news staff do their segments. It’s a painfully sterile and boring room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to the main room, there lies one more doorway, to the deepest part of the station. The desks of the music, assistant music, and program directors lie there. Poster and sticker wise, it has the highest density of the station. going There is a door to a CD archive that contains pictures of some former and current staff, as well as various musicians titled “The Door of Babes”. Finally there is a hallway that leads to the back entrance, a bathroom, and another vinyl/CD archive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">There is a place, hidden in plain sight. Chances are, if you attend or have attended West Virginia University, you have walked by it. Nestled deep inside the student union, there lies a wall of glass, and on the glass the U92 logo proudly rests. This is the college radio station; the source of Morgantown’s only alternative programming, and more importantly: one of my many homes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/personal-blog/dark_station.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Paper Code</title><link href="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/tech/paper-code.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paper Code" /><published>2018-03-30T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/tech/paper-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/tech/paper-code.html">&lt;p&gt;As I’ve become more and more experienced as a programmer, one thing has abundantly clear: the less time you spend writing code, the better. Much like writing a book, if you just hop on your computer and start typing, you’ll eventually find yourself tangled in your own work, making something that is more or less impossible to work with. If you chose to continue working on the same poor foundation, more and more time will be spent dedicated to solving problems that you caused, that could have easily been prevent. It is because of this that the majority of my time is spent carefully deciphering what the problem is and planning out how I will solve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, a factorial program is one of the earliest programming puzzles you may encounter as a rookie programmer. The first step is understanding what a factorial is and how it behaves. This is the point where I whip out the programmer’s primary tools: pen and paper. Looking at the behavior of a factorial, I would trace it by hand on paper. 3 factorial is 1 x 2 x 3, 5 factorial is 1 x 2 x 3 x 4 x 5, and so on. It’s important to recognize the pattern in this situation: every number is multiplied by every factor before it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I know what a factorial is and how it operates, it’s still not time to leave the paper. The next step is the programmers second best friend: charts! I love charts, can’t get enough of them. It’s easy to get lost when following how a program executes, and charts make things clear. First I label it with the function name factorial(&lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt;) (a function is basically a formula that you write yourself). The &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt; value can be any number, so the program I write must be able to work with anything. First I look at cases where the program must fail. You can’t take the factorial of a negative number, or a number that doesn’t exist, so I mark that in a box in the top right. After a quick study of my previous findings, I recognize that I should use a special technique that is common for repeatable processes called recursion. Since taking the factorial of any number requires taking the factorial of the previous number before it, I can chain factorial operations based on what number I take in. It’s a little difficult to comprehend at first, but as an example, take 3 factorial and 2 factorial. 3 factorial is 3 x 2 x 1 and 2 factorial is 2 x 1. Another way to calculate 3 factorial is to multiply 2 factorial by 3. Using this logical, every factorial is essential &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt; x factorial(&lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt;) until &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt; equals 1. If you can’t exactly follow that, don’t think too hard about it. It’s harder to parse that logic in your mind, which is why a chart is essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it’s time to hop on the computer. This should be the easy part. Using whatever language I choose, I take all my notes and write the program. If something goes wrong, I can draw out each step on paper to help understand where I’ve made a mistake. If the solution is completely wrong, I hop off the computer again, and go back to the drawing board. Staring at the screen trying to solve a problem is usually very tiring, and fairly ineffective when it comes to more conceptual problems. Finally, once it’s all said and done, I calculate the factorials of various numbers on paper using a calculator, and input those into the factorial function. If everything checks out, the program is finished.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">As I’ve become more and more experienced as a programmer, one thing has abundantly clear: the less time you spend writing code, the better. Much like writing a book, if you just hop on your computer and start typing, you’ll eventually find yourself tangled in your own work, making something that is more or less impossible to work with. If you chose to continue working on the same poor foundation, more and more time will be spent dedicated to solving problems that you caused, that could have easily been prevent. It is because of this that the majority of my time is spent carefully deciphering what the problem is and planning out how I will solve it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/personal-blog/computerscience.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Flint</title><link href="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/flint.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flint" /><published>2018-03-30T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/flint</id><content type="html" xml:base="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/flint.html">&lt;p&gt;It was another classic day in Morgantown. Cold enough to require a jacket, and hot enough to sweat in one. As I awoke from my light nap, I felt the thick humidity of the air as my shirt stuck to parts of my chest. Groggily, I went over to the kitchen and started the tea kettle for my evening coffee. It was around six in the evening, and I was following the usual thursday routine: go to class, take a nap, and head over to my college’s radio station to prepare for the five hours of music. This time however, I was adding a step. Nick Flynn was doing a reading in the downtown library, and it just so happened that it fit perfectly into my schedule. The little exposure I had of Flynn’s work impressed me, and there was no real reason not to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking into the downtown library, I asked the girl at the counter for directions to the Milano Reading Room. It had been a long time since I had been in this library, and I could exactly recall where it was. Traversing up the stairs, I felt the memories of the reading room rush in. I had only been there twice before to study, but this time it felt completely different. As I walked up the steps, I could hear light chatter slightly echo the wide chamber. Despite being there before,  I couldn’t help but feel an oppressive sense of grandeur while scanning the reading room. I say “room,” but really that’s a bit of a misnomer. In the moment it felt more like a very wide and tall hall than anything else. Dusty old bookcases lined the walls, broken up by old-looking paintings and busts. Looking right, rows of stiff wooden chairs pointed to an empty podium. Decisively avoiding the sugary refreshments, I took a seat in the back row, quietly acknowledging the english professor that mentioned this event to the class. After a minute or two, Will from that same class sat down next to me, and we had a quick chat before the event started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the reading itself, it had all the key points that you can come to expect from a these sorts of events. The somewhat lengthy and numerous introductions. Light humor mixed in, accompanied by that one guy who loudly chuckles at even the smallest quip. That one dude you’re trying very hard not to look at who had started a bunch of “twitter beef” with your friends a few hours earlier. Flynn was by and large, exactly what I expected. The way he manages to write so many words beautifully while only occasionally making things explicitly clear is what drew me to the event in the first place, and his description of the fire he survived as a child did not disappoint. The poetic prose he writes is enthralling, and hearing him read it aloud put a voice to what I had read the day before. The reading itself was fairly short, clocking in at around thirty minutes long. Walking out with Will, I succumbed to my temptation and picked up a chocolate cookie. Finally, I walked out into the rain to head over to my five hour radio shift.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">It was another classic day in Morgantown. Cold enough to require a jacket, and hot enough to sweat in one. As I awoke from my light nap, I felt the thick humidity of the air as my shirt stuck to parts of my chest. Groggily, I went over to the kitchen and started the tea kettle for my evening coffee. It was around six in the evening, and I was following the usual thursday routine: go to class, take a nap, and head over to my college’s radio station to prepare for the five hours of music. This time however, I was adding a step. Nick Flynn was doing a reading in the downtown library, and it just so happened that it fit perfectly into my schedule. The little exposure I had of Flynn’s work impressed me, and there was no real reason not to go.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/personal-blog/water.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Engineering Station</title><link href="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/engineering-station.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Engineering Station" /><published>2018-03-21T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-21T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/engineering-station</id><content type="html" xml:base="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/engineering-station.html">&lt;p&gt;It was early October in the very recent year 2017, and I was standing at the PRT station thinking. The thoughts consumed me, sharply dulling all of my senses. Though the thoughts were focusing on a very bad thing, I strangely felt a neutral feeling while I unpacked each and every one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, do you remember me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly I could see. Before me stood a vaguely recognizable figure. After a short moment putting away my thoughts, I pushed out the words: “Aubri, right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, aren’t you Victor? I remember you from Culturas.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culturas: the student organization for hispanics. It was a name that beckoned the thoughts back.  Again, I paused to put them away. I responded. “How have you been? Haven’t seen you around in a while.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve been doing good, haven’t been to the club in a while sadly.” She paused. “Hey, you’re Puerto Rican right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puerto Rico. The thoughts broke out of the cage again. “Of course, why do you ask?” I knew why she asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How have you been holding up after hurricane Maria? Is your family alright?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s only a few people in my family I haven’t heard from, but they live in the places that didn’t get hit too hard.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I heard the island isn’t getting power back for six months,” said Aubri. Or was it me? The thoughts were screaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, it’s been pretty terrible,” I said. “The island is ruined.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The station lights suddenly flashed the word “BEECHURST”, and it was time for Aubri to leave. “I’m glad you family is at least safe, hope everything ends up okay,” she said before walking away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t recall responding, but I remember thinking about my family. I’ve never had a strong connection to my family, especially the ones that spoke spanish. The language barrier was too strong for me. Yet still, I was worried. Without water, heat stroke was a very real concern. Without power, there was no way to refrigerate my grandmother’s insulin. I was so distant from everything, I heard nothing. The short conversation with my sister I had the day before only fueled my worries. But I couldn’t worry. I had to worry about my studies above all else, and I couldn’t afford to stress about something I could do nothing about. The station lights suddenly flashed the words “WALNUT”, and it was time for me to leave the thoughts behind. Though I haven’t seen Aubri since then, a pleasant thought of her surfaced as I enjoyed my grandmother’s cooking over thanksgiving break. I appreciated it more than I ever have before.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">It was early October in the very recent year 2017, and I was standing at the PRT station thinking. The thoughts consumed me, sharply dulling all of my senses. Though the thoughts were focusing on a very bad thing, I strangely felt a neutral feeling while I unpacked each and every one of them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/personal-blog/station.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Running For Buckthorn</title><link href="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/Running-For-Buckthorn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running For Buckthorn" /><published>2018-02-18T23:50:34-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-18T23:50:34-05:00</updated><id>/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/Running-For-Buckthorn</id><content type="html" xml:base="/personal-blog/blog/nonfiction/Running-For-Buckthorn.html">&lt;p&gt;Running from friends. Running from life. Running from family. No matter where I go, I can’t escape. Running from anxiety. Running from reality. Running from my future career. I’ve never been much of an athlete. My legs and my lungs are always in competition of what will give first. Running from my desires, because I felt like I was never worth them. Running from my needs, because other peoples’ were more important. Running is pointless and exhausting. Trying to justify why you’re running is almost as bad as the act of running itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I’ve been running my whole life. I’ve run figuratively from many things. Trying to avoid my problems, hoping they would go away. I’ve also run from things literally. That’s how I ended up in Morgantown, after all. The first time I ran away from home was at the greatest place on earth; Disney World. I was never a very calm child. What I craved most was excitement and thrills. My parents just wanted to take a nice picture in front of the flowers. Pictures ran very antithetical to what I craved as a child. They made me mad, and I loudly rebelled whenever they were taken. “Where are the roller coasters? I wanna ride the roller coasters,” I can imagine myself demanding loudly. Finally, I snapped. We were at a photo studio for all the Disney characters waiting in line to take a picture with Goofy. Can you imagine waiting in line for something that wasn’t a roller coaster? I was having none of that nonsense. My mother said something very poorly thought out in the moment: “If you don’t like it, you can just leave.” So I did. Eight year old me left his family and started wandering around in Epcot, one of the few Disney World parks without roller coasters, to find a roller coaster. Yet, I was a determined little child, and relentless in my unknowingly pointless search. After around thirty minutes of limitless freedom, I saw a horrifying sight: my aunt in a full speed sprint, high heels in hand. I tried running, but it was too late. She tackled me with full force, and started hitting and yelling at me for leaving and worrying my family. I don’t know what felt worse: the fact that all that running had been for nothing, or the high heels.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor Perez</name></author><summary type="html">Running from friends. Running from life. Running from family. No matter where I go, I can’t escape. Running from anxiety. Running from reality. Running from my future career. I’ve never been much of an athlete. My legs and my lungs are always in competition of what will give first. Running from my desires, because I felt like I was never worth them. Running from my needs, because other peoples’ were more important. Running is pointless and exhausting. Trying to justify why you’re running is almost as bad as the act of running itself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/personal-blog/theland.jpg" /></entry></feed>